Kamaldeen Aiyeleso

Data Analyst

Data analyst with demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry, strong math background and 3 years of experience using descriptive modeling, data processing, data visualization and data mining algorithms to solve challenging business problems.

Lagos, Nigeria. +234 81 744 01 852 Aiyelesok@gmail.com

Portfolio Github

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst — *GatePass*

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

Ensuring quality delivery of analytics reports that enhance accurate and productive business decisions. I actively provided timely updates. Worked on building and maintaining existing dashboards for metrics performances.

Freelance Data Analyst — Fiverr.com

DECEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2021

I worked on clients projects by performing visualization reports and dashboard building using tools like Microsoft Power BI. I provided and received timely updates to relevant parties.

Data Analyst — Lessos Group of Schools, Kwara.

OCTOBER 2018 - OCTOBER 2019

I constantly made use of excel to manage and process student data, plan teachers and students activities and salary disbursement.

PROJECTS

<u>Dataline</u> — A web app that can help restaurant managers plan and optimize their sales towards better profit and resource management.

Catboost, Python, HTML/CSS, JS Script, Flask RestFUL API.

<u>Comparative analysis</u> — A dashboard report created using power BI to compare current sales vs budgeted sales and examine budget variance and YOY%.

Microsoft Power BI

<u>Loan Approval Application</u> — A web app for determining loan eligibility.

Linear Regressor, Python, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Flask API.

<u>Sales Store Forecast</u> — An exploratory and predictive analysis on sales stores.

Python, ARIMA, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib.

EDUCATION

UniversIty of Ilorin, Ilorin — Bachelor of Engineering in Agricultural and Biosystems.

OCTOBER 2012 - OCTOBER 2017

SKILLS

HTML & CSS
Spark and Hadoop
Command Line & Git
Python programming
JavaScript (In view)
Cloud computing (AWS and Azure)
Flask, SQLAlchemy, RESTful APIs
PowerBI, Tableau
Machine Learning
Microsoft Excel for reporting

PERSONALITY HIGHLIGHTS

Decision making
Team player
Great problem solving skills
Meticulous to work under pressure
Time management
Multitasking
Diplomatic and good human
relationship

CERTIFICATIONS

Python for Data Science — *IBM*

December 2020

Certificate of Completion (Power BI) – Linkedin

May 2020

Analyzing data with Power BI - Udemy

May 2020

LANGUAGES

English

REFERENCES

Available on request.